Finding aid to Addie Genevieve Stockwell papers CA.MS.00316
Smith College Archives
Addie Genevieve Stockwell papers
1904-1937
Smith College Archives
Stockwell, Addie Genevieve
CA.MS.00316
0.208 linear feet (1 container)
These papers contain memorabilia and correspondence between Addie Genevieve Stockwell, Class of 1912, and her family and friends.
Biographical / Historical
Addie Genevieve Stockwell was born on November 7, 1889 in West Simsbury, Connecticut to Addie G. Dennison and Samuel F. Stockwell. She attended Simsbury and Hartford schools. She graduated from Smith College in 1912 and went on to hold positions teaching math and science in New York and Connecticut. In 1918, Stockwell attended a nurses training program at Vassar College, and worked in Bellevue Hospital in New York City during the flu epidemic. After her work as a nurse, she returned to teaching in Collinsville, Connecticut. In 1922, she married Harold W. Humphrey, a widow with one son. The couple had four children, two sons and two daughters, and they lived on a dairy farm. Stockwell was active in the Daughters of the American Revolution and remained in touch with former students. She died after a series of strokes in 1944.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of letters are from 1910 to 1912. The letters are mostly between Stockwell and her parents. There are also several letters (including wedding invitations) from other family members, some during the summer from Smith friends. There also correspondence from Stockwell's roommate Ruth Benjamin, Class of 1912. Letters post-1912 are mostly from former students, but there is correspondence with her family as well.
The letters deal with a wide variety of topics. They provide a picture of daily life at home and at college, including descriptions of what Stockwell and her friends in Hubbard House did for fun and her worries about exams and spending money. She mentions Smith traditions such as Mountain Day, the Junior Frolic and Glee Club Concerts, and important individuals such as President Laurenus C. Seelye. Several of the letters also discuss topics of broader historical interest, including a detailed description of her work as a nurse in a New York City Hospital during the 1918 Flu Epidemic, letters from friends serving in World War I, and others which describe the anxieties of the war. She also mentions attending suffragist meetings and seeing an exhibition on child abuse put on by Hull House.
The collection also contains memorabilia from Stockwell's years at Smith, including a commencement program, tuition bill, calling cards, and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Addie Genevieve Stockwell papers were donated to the College Archives by her family.
Smith College - Alumni and alumnae - History - Sources
- Index to the letters (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1904; January-May 1909 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, June 1909; June-September 1910 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, October-November 1910 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, December 1910 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, January-February 1911 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, March-April 1911 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, May-September 1911 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, October 1911 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, November 1911-January 1912 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, February 1912 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, March 1912 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1913; 1917 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1920; 1926; 1937; undated (Box 1)
- Memorabilia, 1908-1912; undated (Box 1)
- Photographs, undated (Box 1)